NATHAN RAFTER

www.nathanrafter.com | nathanrafter@gmail.com | (518)424-0439 | Orlando, FL 32807

EXPERIENCE

Accomplished brand manager, interface designer, and director-level business consultant with over a decade of experience for clientele including ESPN, Sykes Enterprises, and Honda.

Consultant from January 2005-Present

- Senior User Experience Designer for Honda's Roadside Assistance application.
- Lead User Experience Designer for the document repository application Doculent.
- Webmaster and Designer for Atlanta Brave Craig Kimbrel and Tampa Bay Ray Matt Joyce.
- Lead Designer and Digital Marketing Adviser for CraveLocal, a promotions broker for businesses.
- Motionographer for Champion Apparel that produced commercial bumpers and transitions.
- Featured Designer on InstantShift in 2011 and Top Design Mag in 2012.

User Experience Designer at Sykes Enterprises in March-November 2015

- Collaborated with executive leadership to translate business strategies into web-based platforms that currently support over 40,000 active users and continue to drive corporate initiatives.
- Managed over 15 globally distributed team members with diverse backgrounds.
- Appointed Project Manager for 3 enterprise-scale projects. Defined requirements including timeline, production infrastructure, and functional specifications for all final deliverables.
- Developed use case solutions through static wireframe sequences and interactive web-based prototypes. Led virtual and on-site usability tests with groups exceeding 100 users.

Director of Marketing at TeleSpeak from March 2014-January 2015

- Rebranded all products, services, and programs using consistent design language. Glenn Goldberg of Parallel PR said "The rebranding effort has legitimized TeleSpeak."
- Developed company's responsive website that reduced load times to an average of 2 seconds.
- Deployed biweekly email campaigns to over 33,000 subscribers that quadrupled website traffic.
- Produced adverts and authored consumer-focused web content for ChannelVision Magazine.
- Designed trade show booth, attendee experience, and QR code portals for instant engagement.
- Managed vendors Winter Park Blue for signage and GES for trade show booth production.

OVERVIEW

Certificates

- Microsoft Office Specialist
- Project Management Professional
- SharePoint Administration
- Social Engineering

Expertise

Branding and public relations, content creation and distribution, instructional design and presenting, layout and typography, online advertising and search engine optimization, project management, responsive interface design and user experience, trade show design, usability testing, video production

Tools

Productivity suites (Adobe Creative Cloud, Google Office, Microsoft Office), prototyping (Balsamiq, OmniGraffle, Visio), web development (FileZilla, Sublime Text)

Services

Content management (Squarespace, Wordpress), crowdfunding (GoFundMe, Kickstarter), email campaigns (Campaign Monitor, MailChimp), GitHub, Google Adwords, Google Analytics, social networks (Facebook, Twitter), surveying (Google Forms, Survey Monkey), usability testing (Simple Mouse Tracking, UsabilityHub)

NATHAN RAFTER

www.nathanrafter.com | nathanrafter@gmail.com | (518)424-0439 | Orlando, FL 32807

Lab Specialist at Full Sail University from August 2011-March 2014

- Facilitated learning and enhanced curriculum across 13 courses including Web Interface & Usability, Designing for Web Standards, and Rich Media Optimization.
- Updated curriculum for Streaming Media Servers to reflect best practices and address feedback.
- Led monthly extracurricular lectures on topics including branding, color theory, and user experience.
- Marketed the WDDBS Graduate Showcase and formed partnerships with industry leaders including Designzillas, Push, and Rackspace to provide career opportunities for graduates.

Producer at ESPN from February 2011-April 2012

- Directed event coverage, managed diverse production staff, and led star athlete interviews for Twirl
 Mania 2011, the largest baton twirling competition in the US.
- Produced the 2011 Diamond Citrus Classic promos internationally broadcasted on ESPN3.
- Assistant for Tim Tebow and Adam Hubbs during their Make-A-Wish Foundation event in 2011.
- Motionographer that handled animations and bumpers for the ESPN Rise Games.
- Produced highlights for the 2011 Contest of Champions Nationals that collectively received over 250,000 views on YouTube.

EDUCATION

Entertainment Business Master's at Full Sail University from 2010-11

Received the Course Director Award for Brand & Storytelling Development from Ken DeGilio who said
 "You have an intimate understanding of how to build complete brand experiences."

Digital Arts & Design Bachelor's at Full Sail University from 2006-08

• Featured Artist in Full Sail University's 2007 Art Gala.

Technologies

CSS3 and HTML5, Frameworks (Bootstrap, Foundation), Javascript

Platforms

Android, iOS, OS X, Ubuntu, Windows

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Public Speaking

Presented and led workshops based on personal sales techniques at Regional Sales Conferences for Sports Authority; assisted corporate with integrating practices into core employee training programs.

Sales

Recognized 16 times for leading sales at Namco and Sports Authority.

Writing

Authored over 30 articles for industry publications including ChannelVision Magazine and the Web Design & Development blog by Full Sail University.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.